Ever since Dad died,
父亡き後 京都に住まう狸たちから
the tanuki living in Kyoto have called us brothers from Tadasu no Mori
我ら糺の森の兄弟は
“fools who failed to inherit
their great father's blood.”
“立派な父の血を引きそこねた
阿呆たち”と言われてきた
And sure, those gossipy tanuki
might be right every once in a while
口さがない狸たちの陰口が
with the stuff they talk
.about behind our backs,
正鵠を射ていることもたまにはあろう
but saying it as if our father's blood
just disappeared into thin air
しかしながら
父の血がどこやらへ
雲散霧消したかのような言い草は
really pisses me off.
いくら何でも業腹だ
For one thing, all tanuki are
.fools to some extent as it is.
大体 狸は皆 多かれ少なかれ阿呆なのである
To take it a step further,
さらに言えば 阿呆であることこそ
I'd say that very idiocy is the best proof there is that his blood flows through our veins.
我らが父の血を引いている証に他ならない
After reaching the apex of tanuki society,
父は狸界の頂点を極めた後
Dad's own foolishness caught up to him,
and he ascended to the state of stew.
“阿呆”が高じて鍋となったのだ
Episode Eleven
Back in the Game
Would you be so good as to just give up and come with us, Yasaburou?
観念して一緒に来てもらおうか
-くっ
-矢三郎
What are you doing, Ebisugawa?
-何をしているの？　夷川
-お?! ん
Such tiresome rain.
ひどい雨
I'm happy to find you in
.good humor, Miss Benten.
弁天様 ご機嫌麗しゅう
Do I look good-humored to you?
麗しくないって言ってるでしょうが
I was waiting out the rain up there
.when I saw you, Yasaburou.
上で雨宿りしてたんだけれども
矢三郎がそこにいるからね
Then I thought I'd have you transform
.into an umbrella for me.
傘に化けてもらおうと思って
I'd transform into anything for you,
Benten—umbrellas included.
そりゃあもう弁天様のためなら
傘にでも何でも化けます
But...
いや しかし
What is it, Ebisugawa?
なあに夷川
Is there a problem with that?
何か文句があるの？
We were just about to head
.to a reconciliation banquet.
これから仲直りの宴へ出掛けるところでしてね
If you were to take him away,
ここで弁天様が矢三郎をお連れになられると
we would be left in
.quite the predicament.
私としては大変困るのです
Remind me again: how does your
predicament concern me in the slightest?
あなたが困ると言うけれど
私に何の関係があるのかしら
Are you suggesting I should walk home
like this, soaked to the bone?
それともあなたは
私にこのまま濡れて帰れと言うつもり？
Of course not. I wouldn't dream of it.
いえいえ 滅相もございません
Then I'll just borrow him for a bit.
ではちょっとお借りしますよ
んっ
Awful weather, huh?
ひどい天気ね
You saved me. Thank you.
おかげで助かりました
ありがとうございます
Did I do something?
私が何かした？
No need to thank me.
お礼を言うことはないわ
I went to Master's room the day
.before yesterday, on Christmas Eve.
一昨日のイブの夜
お師匠様のアパートに行ったわ
あ 何故です？
What for?
I'd had a few drinks for
.the first time in a while,
久しぶりに酔っ払っちゃったから
so I thought it wouldn't be
.so bad to check in on him.
たまには先生の顔でも見ようと思って
He was sleeping like a log, though,
so I went home right away.
ぐっすりと寝ていらしたから すぐに帰ったけど
You gave him that cane, did you not?
あのステッキは
あなたがプレゼントしたものでしょう？
No present for me?
私にはプレゼントは無いの？
No.
ありませんよ
Why not?
何故？
There's nothing you'd
need from me, is there?
弁天様に欲しいものなんか無いでしょう？
You already get whatever you want.
何でも手に入れるくせに
That's a terrible thing to say.
ひどいこと言うのね
I haven't gotten a single
.thing I've ever wanted.
欲しいものなんか何一つ手に入らないわ
ん
You're pretty quiet today, aren't you?
今日は随分と無口なのね
I know you put Father in a
.cage for the Ebisugawas.
あなたは夷川に頼まれて
父上を罠に嵌めたでしょう
Why didn't you ever say anything?
何故黙っていたのです？
Huh?
え？
You never asked!
だって聞かれなかったもの
I can't believe how much you
.humans like to twist words.
まったく人間という奴は質が悪い
I'll have you know I'm a tengu.
私は天狗よ
Nope. You're a human,
and you'll always be a human.
いや 人間ですよ どうしたって人間です
Is that why you're giving
me the cold shoulder?
それで怒って無口なの？
It's not just that.
それだけじゃないんですよ
It seems my brothers have been
.captured by the Ebisugawas.
兄貴たちが夷川に捕まったらしいんです
You know how today is the
Friday Fellows' year-end bash?
今日は金曜倶楽部の忘年会でしょう
They might end up making
.my big brother into stew.
兄貴が鍋にされるかもしれない
Good heavens!
おやまあ
So I'll be eating your big brother tonight?
じゃあ私は今夜あなたのお兄さんを食べるの？
How terrible!
大変ね
Would you be able to save him for me?
兄貴を助けてやって下さいませんか？
Don't count on it.
知らない
Why? You won't save him
just because he's a tanuki?
何故です？
狸だから助けてくれないのですか？
I'm only human, you know.
だって私は人間だもの
ん
In that case, I'll do something
.about it on my own.
じゃあ 自分で何とかする
Where are the Friday Fellows
having their get-together?
金曜倶楽部はどこでやるんです？
Chitose-ya in Pontochou.
先斗町の千歳屋
Do me a favor and try not to charge
.in there with your fists flying.
でも殴り込んできたりしないでちょうだいね
You're always so quick to
.resort to violence. I hate it.
あなたはそうやって
すぐに乱暴なことをするのだから嫌
Professor Yodogawa was saying he would
.go pick up the tanuki this afternoon.
淀川教授は今日の午後
狸を引き取りに出掛けると仰っていたわ
He said he was in touch with someone who
.caught one, and they'd made an agreement.
狸を捕まえた人と連絡が付いて
そういう約束をしたんですって
Oh, right. Professor Yodogawa.
なるほど 淀川教授か
You can figure the rest out by yourself.
後は自分で何とかなさい
I'm human, so I just eat whatever
.tanuki ends up in the stew.
だって私は人間なのだから
鍋になった狸を食べるだけ
I couldn't care less who it is.
痛くも痒くもないのだもの
ん？
Professor Yodogawa?
淀川教授
It's like he just fell into my lap.
まるであつらえたようではないか
This is it! Divine providence!
これぞまさに天佑神助
Chikurintei Soba Noodles
Excuse me!
すいません
ん？
あ
I'll have an egg bowl.
玉子丼を一つ
ん ここから出せ！
Let me out of here!
Dammit!
ん くそ
Yaichirou?
-矢一郎かい
-ん?!
んん
Mother?
母上！
あっ
Mother!
母上！
Yaichirou, they got you too?
矢一郎 お前も捕まったのだね
I'll save you, Mother!
母上 今お助けしますから
ぐう くく 出られん ちっくしょう
Dammit, I can't get out!
Once you're put in a cage, there's
.nothing you can do, Yaichirou.
檻に入れられてしまったら
どうしようもないよ 矢一郎
You tried to get to me because Raijin
brought his storms, didn't you?
雷神様が来たから
私の所へ来てくれようとしたんだね
It's my fault.
お前には悪いことをしたよ
うう
This all happened because
.of my fear of thunder.
-私が雷神様に弱いばっかりに
-く ぐうう
-こんなことになって
-く うう
そんなことはいいのです
None of that matters!
I wonder what happened to
.Yasaburou and Yashirou.
矢三郎や矢四郎はどうしたかしら
I hope they're not having
.too rough of a time.
痛い思いをしていなければいいけれど
This is an Ebisugawa conspiracy!
ん 夷川の陰謀ですよ
How can they do this as fellow tanuki?
狸のくせに何ということをする
Drop dead!
ん くたばれ！
くしゅん
Are you okay, Mother?
あ 大丈夫ですか 母上
I'm just a bit cold.
少し冷えただけ　くしゅん
ああ
That's strange.
妙だな
ふう　んん
うう う　んん
ああ
“Back in the game, you know my name.”
捲土重来 けれどちょうだい
Yashirou?
矢四郎？
We're back in the game!
捲土重来！
Back in the Game
ん くっ
You drugged the egg bowl?
玉子丼に一服盛るとは
We tricked him good, didn't we, big bro?
うまく化かしてやったね 兄さん
Well done, Ginkaku.
良くやったよ銀閣
うう くたば れ
Drop d—
Gentlemen,
さて諸君
the day of vindication has arrived!
雪辱の日は来たれり
Yay!
いえい
Chikurintei
Demachi
shopping arcade
Masugata Co-op
くしゅん
We have some ready for you in here.
こちらに揃えてあります
あ？
ふっ
How many do you need, Juroujin?
いかほどご入用ですか 寿老人様
Benten will be there,
弁天さんがおるからな
so we'll need to prepare
.enough for ten people.
十人前は用意しておかねばならんな
ん？
おやおやおや こんな所に狸がおるではないか
Oh my,
if it isn't the tanuki. Here, of all places.
Yes. I made an agreement to turn
.him over for tonight's banquet.
これは今宵の宴にお渡しする約束で
そうかい 布袋さんはやはり他人頼みか
Ah, so Hotei asked someone
.else to get one for him.
How pathetic.
情けないことだな
This soft spot for tanuki that
.Hotei has is really no good.
どうも布袋さんはこの頃
狸のことになると腰が引けていかん
That's where I come in.
それで 私が一肌脱ぐことになりまして
So you run this kind of
racket as well, Ebisugawa?
お前はそういう商売もしていたのか夷川
What an utterly wicked fellow you are.
まったく悪い奴だのう
Please, you flatter me.
恐れ入ります
So there'll be two tanuki tonight?
では今宵は狸が二匹か
Splendid!
-豪儀なことよ
-ああ
Oh, I'm sorry. This one isn't available.
これはいけません これはいけません
Just one, then?
一匹だけか？
たとえ寿老人様の仰ることでも
I'm afraid I can't give up
.this tanuki, Juroujin.
Not even to you yourself.
こちらの狸はお譲りできません
You're fond of that one, I take it?
お前のお気に入りということかね
It is as you say.
その通りでございます
Well, that's fine.
まあいいわ
Bring these to Chitose-ya.
これを千歳屋まで届けておくれ
Understood.
はっ
ん んんっ
Dammit!
くそっ！ ぐぎぎ ぐうっ
I won't let them make you into stew!
お前を鍋にしてたまるもんですか
んんっ
But there's nothing we
.can do at the moment.
でも今のところ打つ手が無いね
ん…
If there's anyone who could
.save us, it'd be Yasaburou,
我々を助けられるとすれば 矢三郎ですが
but he's probably been
.captured already.
あいつも捕まっているでしょう
そうでないと早雲が
If he hadn't been, there's no way Soun
.would have been that laid back.
あんなに落ち着いていられるはずがない
We can't give up.
諦めてはいけないよ
Yasaburou is sharp and fearless,
矢三郎はすばしっこいし 恐いもの知らずだから
so I'm sure he'll be okay.
きっと大丈夫だと私は思うよ
Hey, Kinkaku, let me outta here!
やい金閣 ここから出せ！
Why doesn't a pro like you
just transform his way out?
お得意の化け術で変じればどうだい？
Oh, you mean you can't 'cause
you're locked up in a cage?
ダメか？　そんな所に閉じ込められていては
That's right, big bro.
そうだよ兄さん
To transform, you gotta have "inner calm."
化けるには心の余裕ってものがないと
Right, right.
そうだったそうだった
And at the moment, he doesn't have the
slightest bit of inner calm, does he?
今彼には心の余裕なんて微塵も無いもんね
Too bad!
それは仕方ない
ははは ははは…
You rotten jerks are a disgrace
to all of tanuki-kind!
狸界の風上にも置けぬ腐れ狸め！
Goodness me, could it be that
you're just a plain old fool?
お前はあれかい？
ひょっとして阿呆なのかい？
No doubt about it, big bro.
阿呆さきっと 兄さん
Clearly, a fool like you is too foolish
.to know where he went wrong.
阿呆なお前には何が起こったのか分かるまい
So I'll tell you.
だから僕が教えてあげよう
I predicted you would follow Professor
.Yodogawa to try to save Yaichirou.
お前が淀川教授の後をつけて
矢一郎を助けようとするのが
僕にはお見通しだったのだ
Predicted!
お見通し
Even so, no matter how
.brilliant my transformation,
それにしても
いくら僕の化け術が素晴らしいからといって
you must have been blind as a bat
.not to pick him out as a fake.
偽教授だと見抜けないとはお前の目は節穴だね
Aren't you supposed to be friends with him?
教授とは仲良しだったんじゃないのかい？
Kinkaku, Ginkaku! When I get outta this cage,
I'm gonna bust your asses into eight cheeks each!
金閣 銀閣 檻から出たら
尻を八つに割ってやるからな！
That makes sixteen between you!
合わせて十六分割だ！
Who cares about your powers of addition?
足し算なんて知らないよ
It might be multiplication, big bro.
掛け算かもしれないよ兄さん
Hmm? Two times eight is sixt—
え？　二が四つでじゅうろ
Well, either way,
ま どっちにしろ僕らはね
長浜在住の鍛冶職人が渋々作った
we're wearing our iron underwear made reluctantly
.by an artisan blacksmith in Nagahama,
鉄のパンツを履いているからへいちゃらさ
so we're cool as cucumbers!
へいちゃら へいちゃら
Cool as cucumbers!
We even stuck hand warmers in 'em
.so our butts wouldn't get cold.
しかもそこへカイロを入れておいたんだから
お尻も冷えない
Such a bulletproof plan must
be the work of a genius!
この抜かりない計画 天才ではなかろうか
Heaven's vengeance is slow but sure!
天網恢々疎にして漏らさず
My big bro came up with all of this himself.
全部兄さん独自のアイディアだ
Meticulous planning!
用意周到 用意周到
Ready to throw in the towel, Yasaburou?
参ったかい 矢三郎
何のまだまだ 参らないね
What, already? Not on your life!
あはんはんはんはんはん
You stubborn jackass!
この意地っ張りめ！
This is a plan that I've been
carefully putting together
これは去年から僕がこの明晰な頭脳を使って
in my brilliant mind since last year!
慎重に組み立てていた計画なのだ
Our father's already turning that pitiful Yaichirou
over to Professor Yodogawa, you know?
哀れな矢一郎君は
父上が淀川教授に引き渡すだろう
Your tail-popping little brother is in a
.warehouse at the fake Denki Bran factory,
あの尻尾丸出しの弟は
偽電気ブラン工場の倉庫の中だけれど
but we slapped on a padlock as big as his head,
so he's not getting out any time soon.
鏡餅みたいに大きな南京錠を掛けてきたから
どうしたって逃げられない
We've also got your mother.
君の母上もこちらの手の中だ
And you're here, crammed in a
.cage inside Ginkaku's stomach.
そうして君はここ
銀閣のお腹の中で檻に詰め込まれてる
So where's that white flag, huh?
さ これでも参らないか？
Who's gonna save you, and how?
誰がどうやって助けてくれる？
Yajirou is still out there!
まだ矢二郎兄さんがいるぞ！
プププププ
You're so stupid!
バカだな あんな井戸の中の蛙に
What do you think that
frog in a well can do?
何ができるって言うんだ
The Shimogamo family is over.
下鴨家はてんでバラバラさ
All we have to do now is
.wait for the sun to go down.
後は日が暮れるのを待つばかりというわけだよ
Rest in peace.
-南無阿弥陀仏
-プププププ
May Yaichirou reach enlightenment
.right after he reaches the stew pot.
-お鍋になっちゃう矢一郎君 成仏してくれたまえ
-プププププ
-南無阿弥陀仏　南無阿弥陀仏
-プププププ　プププププ
Rest in peace, rest in peace.
Damn you!
こんにゃろ いくら阿呆の狸でも
We may be stupid tanuki, but
there are lines we mustn't cross!
やってよいことと悪いことがあるぞ！
I won't be lectured by a dope like you.
阿呆なお前の説教なんて聞きたくもないね
As Yaichirou ascends to the stew pot,
so shall our father ascend to Nise-emon.
矢一郎はお鍋になり 父上が偽右衛門になる
And then somewhere down
.the line, I'll inherit that title.
そしてゆくゆくは僕が偽右衛門の名を継ぐのだ
I'll be the clever, strong, young ray of hope
that will shoulder the future of all tanuki-kind!
狸界の未来を背負って立つ
賢く強い若手のホープとは僕のことだ
そうとも！
Quite right!
あ 電池が無くなるまで長電話してやろう
Let's talk 'til the battery runs out.
Oh, Kaisei?
あ 海星？　兄ちゃん
It's your big bro.
Hold tight 'til tonight, okay?
いっ いや いや 夜まで我慢しておくれよ
No, you can't now.
い 今はダメ
竹林亭で矢三郎をとっちめてるんだ
We're at Chikurintei teaching
Yasaburou a lesso—
ああ あ あ
Please don't talk like that.
あ お お願いだからそんなこと言うなよ
You're wounding your big brother terribly.
兄ちゃんはひどく傷付くじゃないか
Then I hope you drop dead
from those wounds!
傷付け！ その傷が元でくたばれ！
C'mon, don't be like that.
ん 頼むからそんなこと言うなよ
You're an unmarried girl.
嫁入り前の女の子なんだからね
Right?
いいかい　もっと自分を大事にするんだよ
So take better care of yourself.
Then quit screwing aro—
だったら今すぐバカなことは止めろ
I'm just looking out for her...
あの子のためを思えばこそなんだけどなァ
Your little sister doesn't have
any respect for either of you!
お前 妹に全然尊敬されておらんじゃないか
Who asked you?
いらんお世話だ！
Yeah, who?
お世話だ！
Mother!
母上！
Mother, are you all right?
母上！ 大丈夫ですか？
Are you feeling cold?
あ 寒くはないですか
あ 母上？
Mother!
I'm all right.
大丈夫だよ
寒くないよ
I'm not cold.
あ
You didn't move a muscle, so I got worried.
ちょっとも動かないから心配になりました
I'm conserving energy.
力を温存しているんだよ
If you try to struggle,
you'll just hurt your bottom.
暴れたってお尻が痛くなるだけだもの
あ はぁ
あ ぐぃっ
The professor has arrived.
教授がお見えだ
Once I turn you over, I'm going to Sensuiro.
お前を引き渡してから俺は仙酔楼へ行く
Just leave the future of tanuki-kind to me.
狸界の将来は俺に任せておくがよい
Farewell, Yaichirou.
さらばだ矢一郎 神妙にお鍋になれ
Please go gentle into that good stew.
Drop dead!
くたばれ！
You think I'm gonna just
let you have your way?
お前の思い通りになってたまるか！
I'm not gonna cheerfully dive
into your damned stewpot!
そう簡単に鍋にはならんぞ！
I've got your mother in
.the palm of my hand.
お前の母親の身柄は俺の手の内にある
If you were to run, what do you
think would happen to her?
お前が逃げたらどうなると思う
どれだけ卑怯になったら気が済むんだ！
How low must you stoop
before you're satisfied?!
No matter what you say, your
.words will never reach me.
何と言われても屁でもないわ
Mr. Ebisugawa.
-夷川さん
-ん
あなたはそこまで変わってしまったのね
You really have changed so much.
I think it's a dreadful shame.
私は大変残念に思うよ
総さんだってきっとそう思ってるよ
I'm sure Sou would say the same.
If he knew his little brother had become such
.a horrible tanuki, he would be crushed.
弟がこんな酷いことをする狸になったと知ったら
総さんは悲しむよ
"Sou," huh? He was fully aware of it.
総さんかい
兄貴は先刻ご承知だよ
Tanuki don't do such
.horrible things to each other.
こんなひどいことは狸のすることじゃないよ
This is something a tengu or a human
would do, Mr. Ebisugawa!
まるで天狗や人間のすることじゃないの
夷川さん
Mr. Ebisugawa,
夷川さん お願いだから
I'm begging you, please
.stop bullying my children.
もううちの子供たちをいじめるのはやめておくれ
And yet, you call me “Ebisugawa."
あんたは俺を夷川と呼ぶ
But that's who you are.
だってあなたは夷川だもの
Then what do the children you had
with my brother have to do with me?
では あんたと兄貴の子供たちが
俺に何の関係があろう
If you get the chance to escape,
take it! Don't worry about me!
-逃げる隙があったら構わずお逃げ
-母上！
Mother!
う うっ
Hello there.
やあ どうも
So this is the one.
この子だね
Indeed. Here he is, as promised.
お約束通り 用意しておきました
What a magnificent li'l guy.
立派な子だね
But you know, tonight
.we're gonna eat you up.
だけどね
今夜 我々はお前を食べてしまうんだよ
うう
ん？
んっ
あぁ
ん？
んん んん うう うう…うっ ふう
うう う！ わ わあ！
あ
ん？
んん
あ
That's...
あれは
んっ ん
うっ…いっ い　いっ！
Yashirou!
矢四郎君
-矢四郎君
-あっ！
Yashirou!
ん えっ
Kaisei, get me outta here!
海星姉ちゃん ここから出して！
I can't. It's locked.
鍵がかかっててダメ
But I gotta hurry!
でも 僕は早く行かなくちゃならないんだ
I know. Calm down.
分かってるから落ち着いて
There's a hidden hatch in the corner
.of the warehouse. Find that.
倉庫の隅に隠し扉があるから それを探しなさい
If you undo the latch from
.inside, you can get out.
内側から閂を外せば出られる
Thanks!
ありがとう
Where are my brothers?
兄ちゃんたちは？
Yaichirou was taken
.by the Friday Fellows.
矢一郎さんは金曜倶楽部に捕まった
Kinkaku said on the phone earlier that he and
.Ginkaku were teaching Yasaburou a lesson.
金閣と銀閣は矢三郎をとっちめるって
さっき電話で言ってた
And Mother? Is Mother here, too?
母上は？　母上もここにいる？
They got her as well, but
.she's not here at the factory.
伯母様も捕まったけれど
この工場にいないのは
My dad must have her
.locked up somewhere else.
きっとお父さんがどこかよそへ
閉じ込めているんだわ
Probably at the fake Denki Bran shop.
多分 偽電気ブランの販売所
How can they be so cruel?!
ひどい奴ら
矢三郎を助ければ何とかなる
If we can save Yasaburou,
it'll all work out somehow.
あっ！
This won't do, young mistress.
いけませんお嬢様！
Please return to your room.
さあ お部屋にお戻りください
We'll be scolded by Master Soun!
我々が早雲様に叱られます
Run.
走るよ
-えっ わ！
-んっ
Young mistress!
お嬢様！
んっ
-えっ
-わ
ああ
ん　んんっ
Go to Chikurintei!
竹林亭へ行って！
If I go by myself, Kinkaku and Ginkaku
.will beat me to a pulp.
僕だけじゃ金閣と銀閣に
こてんぱんに やられちゃうよ
Come with me and tell them to stop!
姉ちゃんも一緒に来て
金閣と銀閣にガツンと言ってやってよ
If I go with you, all of these
.guys will be after us.
私といたらこの人たち全員に追われちゃう
You're going alone!
一人で行くの！
あ
え？
わ わ わああー！
Put your tail away and run for it!
尻尾をしまって
-早く走れええええ！
-んっ
えっ ふう ふう
We take pride in our position
阿呆高じて崇高となる
as lords of the realm of idiocy.
我らはそれを誇りとする
As reflections of the idiot blood that
.flowed through the veins of our father,
我らの父も そのまた父も
下鴨家の狸たちは代々 その身の内に流れる
his father, and generations
.of the Shimogamo family,
阿呆の血のしからしむるところによって
sometimes we trick humans,
sometimes we harass tengu,
時に人間を化かし 時に天狗を陥れ
and sometimes we wind up as stew.
時に煮え立つ鉄鍋へ転げ落ちてきた
These aren't things to be ashamed of,
but things of which we should be proud.
これは恥じるべきことではなく
誇るべきことである
Know that we brothers hold our
.heads high with that pride,
たとえ涙が滲んでも
それでもなお誇るところに
even—and especially—when our
.eyes are brimming with tears.
我ら兄弟の面目があると知れ
繋いだ手を振りほどけば
You shake off my hand
tsunaida te wo furihodokeba
いたずらに 君微笑む
and idly smile at me
itazura ni kimi hohoemu
春は嵐 ざわざわする
Spring is ripe with the roll of thunder,
haru wa arashi zawazawa suru
もう花びら散りすぼんだ
and some cherry blossoms have already left the branches
mou hanabira chirisubonda
口癖はケセラセラ
Your favorite phrase is "Que será, será"
kuchiguse wa que sera sera
また呟く声がする
I can hear you whisper it again
mata tsubuyaku koe ga suru
彼女はいつもさよなら言わずに
She always vanishes
kanojo wa itsumo
sayonara
without saying "Goodbye,"
iwazu ni
風と消える
just like the wind
kaze to kieru
I don't know what the future will be like,
mirai no koto wa wakaranai keredo
未来のことはわからないけれど
今ここにある奇蹟は僕のものと
but I'll have faith
ima koko ni aru
that little miracles
kiseki wa
are awaiting me
boku no mono to shinjiteru
信じてる
約束なんてしたくないけれど
I don't want to be tied down by promises,
yakusoku nante shitakunai keredo
but let's hold up our hands
sono te wo kazashite
その手をかざして確かなもの
and find something,
tashika na mono
手に入れよう
something permanent
te ni ireyou
それは僕らを輝かす
that will
sore wa
show just who we are
bokura wo kagayakasu
小さな檻の中じゃ心細くもなるけれど
Being in a tiny cage makes you feel helpless,
but if anyone can get through this, it's our kids!
あの子たちならきっと大丈夫
ね 総さん
Right, Sou?
Next Time:
The False Eizan Electric Railway